ALI ZAHID

MY GITHUB REPOSITORIES

https://github.com/AliZahid117?tab=repositories

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am enthusiastic and passionate about software development. Currently, I am on a government-funded software development boot camp and self-learning online from Codeacademy's full-stack engineering course. I have been building various projects in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, which I have linked on this CV to my GitHub repositories, and my website is linked on this CV. From making my first computer at the age of eight to now learning how to code I have always been fascinated by computers. I have proven skills in project management from seven years managing a property business, I also have international experience working in America and Belgium.

WORK HISTORY

Manager, 08/2017 – 02/2024 Z Properties, London

- Seven years managing a family property portfolio of five houses.
- Responsibilities as manager included: preparing the yearly tax return, hiring, and managing builders for repairs and refurbishments on the houses, acquiring new and maintaining existing tenants, and dealing with tenant queries.
- I built positive relationships with my tenants to maintain the high standards of the company brand.
- Identified, planned, and implemented new real estate projects.
- Carried out refurbishments on the houses to increase profits by over 50% from the rent and saved the business money by building two kitchens by myself.

Camp counsellor/ Lifeguard, 06/2019 – 08/2019 Camp America/ Kennolyn Camps, Soquel California

- International experience working as a camp counsellor in America through Camp America.
- My roles were: Counsellor, lifeguard, guitar instructor, and basketball coach.
- Worked as a professionally qualified RLSS UK lifeguard.
- Participated in meetings to coordinate with other staff on the camper's progress, issues, and goal achievements.
- Implemented camp activities fostering physical, social, and emotional growth.

Night shop assistant, 05/2022 – 09/2022 Nachtwinkel Lochristi Lo-Bravo, Belgium, Lochristi

- International experience in Belgium dealing with customers and fostering positive customer relationships.
- Prepared invoices for customers with large and special orders.

- 1 Bushey Road, London UB3
 4AS
- 07944588500
- alizahid98@live.co.uk
- https://alizahid117.github.io./

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- HTML, CSS
- Git
- GitHub
- Problem-solving
- Leadership and management skills
- Business administration and commercial awareness
- Revenue growth and brand management

EDUCATION

A-Levels, Biology, History, 09/2015 - 07/2017

Harlington School - London

- Biology C
- History C

GCSEs, 09/2012 - 07/2014 Harlington School - London

- 1 A (Biology A)
- 8 B's (Math's B, English B)

HOBBIES

- Guitar
- Programming
- Swimming